Claire Falkenstein
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Artwork, circa 1937-1995, Series 9:; (Box 36-37, 44, 57; 2.0 linear feet)
  The sketchbooks are first arranged chronologically, followed by specific media. Works of art by others are found at the end of the series.
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1944 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1950 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Sketchbook, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Sketchbook, 1954-1955 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Sketchbook, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbook, 1974, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1977-1978, (3 folders) (Box 36, Folder 8-10)
  - Sketchbooks, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 36, Folder 11-12)
  - Sketchbook - Ideas for Screens, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1985-1995, (10 folders) (Box 36, Folder 14-23)
  - Sketchbook - TV Portraits, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Sketchbook - Wrestlers and Swimmers, 1988-1989 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Sketchbooks, Undated, (2 folders) (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - Sketchbook - First Impressions of Paris, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Anatomical Sketches and Drawings, Undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - "Chalice" Sketches, circa 1960-1970 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - "Conic" Section Sketches, circa 1969 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Color Ideas, circa 1980 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Gondola Ticket Art Sketches, circa 1963 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Hands, circa 1975 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Hanging Gardens Sketches and Drawings, circa 1950-1959, (Oversized items housed in Box 44) (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Jewelry Sketches, circa 1956 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Kinetic Sculpture Sketches, circa 1953 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - "Love" Sketches and Drawings, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Pignatelli Gate Sketches, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Portrait of Michel Tapie, 1956 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Portraits, circa 1990 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - "Predator" Sketches, circa 1963 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Ships, Undated (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Southern France and Spain, circa 1950-1951 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Spain, 1951 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Stained Glass and "Conic" Pieces, circa 1970 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Topological Structures, circa 1977 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Trip to Reims, 1953 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Sketches and Drawings, circa 1939-1987, Undated, (17 folders, oversized items housed in Box 44 and OV 57) (Box 37, Folder 24-40)
  - Artwork by Others - Frank Assetto, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 41)
  - Artwork by Others - H. Burkhardt, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 42)
  - Artwork by Others - Child's Drawing, Undated (Box 37, Folder 43)
  - Artwork by Others - Adelyne Cross, circa 1937-1955 (Box 37, Folder 44)
  - Artwork by Others - Corky Korhowski, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 45)
  - Artwork by Others - Berto Morucchio, 1961, (Oversized item housed in Box 44) (Box 37, Folder 46)
  - Artwork by Others - Margaret de Patta, 1946-1949 (Box 37, Folder 47)
  - Artwork by Others - Leon Saulter, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 48)
  - Artwork by Others - School Children in Africa, Undated (Box 37, Folder 49)
  - Artwork by Others - R. A. Smith, Undated (Box 37, Folder 50)
  - Artwork by Others - Vicki Thorpe, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 51)
  - Artwork by Others - Mark Tobey, 1954, (Oversized item housed in Box 44) (Box 37, Folder 52)
  - Artwork by Others - Don Walters, Undated (Box 37, Folder 53)
  - Artwork by Others - Students, circa 1960-1989 (Box 37, Folder 54)
  - Artwork by Others, Undated (Box 37, Folder 55)
  - Wine Labels, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 56)
  - Oversized Artwork by Others - Mark Tobey, circa 1954, (from Box 37, F. 52) (Box 44)
  - Oversized Artwork by Others - Douglas Macagy, circa 1950 (Box 44)
  - Oversized Sketch of Sculpture with Base, Undated (Box 44)
  - Oversized Sketch for Ray Green Program "Holiday for 4," 1946 (Box 44)
  - Oversized Drawing by Michel Tapie, Mark Tobey, and Claire Falkenstein, 1954 (Box 44)
  - Drawing for "DNA Molecule" Turntable, circa 1970 (Box 44)
  - Oversized Artwork by Others - Christmas Card, Undated (Box 44)
  - Oversized Sketch of Stairwell Mural for Donald Olsen, 1956 (Box 44)
  - Oversized Hanging Gardens Sketches and Drawings, 1959, (from Box 37, F. 10) (Box 44)
  - Oversized Joseph Bransten Table, 1948 (Box 44)
  - Oversized Miscellaneous Drawings and Sketches, circa 1947-1958, (from Box 37, F. 24) (Box 44)
  - Oversized Sketchbooks, circa 1950-1971, (from Box 37, F. 2-6) (Box 44)
  - Oversized Animal Sketches, Undated (Box 44)
  - Oversized Miscellaneous Drawings and Sketches, circa 1940-1990, (4 sheets); (from Box 37, F. 24) (Box OV 57)
  - Oversized Drawings by Others - Berto Morucchio, 1963, (2 sheets); (from Box 37, F. 46) (Box OV 57)
  - Oversized Artwork by Others - Paul and Nolene Showalter, 1996 (Box OV 57)
- Printed Materials, circa 1914-1990, Series 10:; (Box 37-40, 45, 58; 3.9 linear feet)
  This series contains a fairly complete set of catalogs, announcements, and newspaper clippings, all documenting Falkenstein exhibitions and other activities. Also included are several copies of View, an American art and literary magazine published from 1940 to 1947. The books in this series are either inscribed by the author or signed and dated by Falkenstein.
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1940-1962, (8 folders) (Box 37, Folder 57-64)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1963-1997, (16 folders) (Box 38, Folder 1-16)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements - Other Artists, 1948-1969, (3 folders) (Box 38, Folder 17-19)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements - Other Artists, 1970-1989, (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1940-1997, (11 folders) (Box 39, Folder 3-13)
  - Issues of the View, 1943-1946, (3 folders) (Box 39, Folder 14-16)
  - Oversized - Printed Materials, 1950-1990, (Oversized items housed in Box 45 and OV 58) (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Poems Madi by Kosice Golse-se, 1945, (Inscribed as a Gift) (Box 39, Folder Books)
  - Childhood Bible (Box 39)
  - Native Son by Richard Wright, 1940, (Inscribed as a Gift) (Box 39)
  - Round Table Art Book - Teachers Edition by Cora Elder Stafford, 1930 (Box 39)
  - Le Principe D'Antagonisme et La Logique De L'Energie by Stephane Lupasco, 1951, (Inscribed as a Gift) (Box 39)
  - Poems in English by L. Vroman, 1953, (Inscribed as a Gift) (Box 39)
  - Jeunes Peintres, Musee National D'Art Moderne, 1955 (Box 39)
  - Introduction to Human Anatomy by William K. Gregory, 1942 (Box 39)
  - Ancient Times: A History of the Early World by James Henry Breasted, 1914 (Box 39)
  - Claire Falkenstein: Chance and Choice, Jack Rutberg Fine Arts, circa 1988 (Box 40, Folder Books)
  - Claire Falkenstein by Michel Tapie, 1958, (Inscribed by Author) (Box 40)
  - Painting and Sculpture, The San Francisco Art Association, 1952 (Box 40)
  - The Group presents OTIS '73, Otis Art Institute, 1973 (Box 40)
  - 50 West Coast Artists: A Critical Selection of Painters and Sculptors Working in California by Henry Hopkins, 1981 (Box 40)
  - Issue of Il Cerchio, Quarterly Magazine of Contemporary Art, circa 1970 (Box 40)
  - Issue of L'Arte Moderna, 1967, (Volume 8, Number 116) (Box 40)
  - Craftsman Lifestyle: the Gentle Revolution by Olivia H. Emery, 1977 (Box 40)
  - La Collezione Peggy Guggenheim, circa 1965 (Box 40)
  - Laurel Songs: Student Edition by M. Teresa Armitage, 1914, (Property of Oakland Public Schools) (Box 40)
  - My French Conversational Guide, 1945 (Box 40)
  - The Modern Reader's Bible, 1917 (Box 40)
  - The Aesthetic Attitude by Herbert Sidney Langfeld, 1920 (Box 40)
  - The Solstice Tree by Julia Randall, 1953, (Inscribed by Author) (Box 40)
  - No Way to Build a Ballpark and Other Irreverent Essays on Architecture by Allan Temko, 1993, (Inscribed by Author) (Box 40)
  - Petits Contes de France by Albert A. Meras, 1916 (Box 40)
  - The Life of Michelangelo Buonarroti by John Addington Symonds, Undated (Box 40)
  - Kingdom of God is Within You. What is Art? What is Religion by Lyof N. Tolstoi, 1927 (Box 40)
  - Since Cezanne by Clive Bell, 1923, (Inscribed as a Gift) (Box 40)
  - Salt and Seeds by Virginia Russ, 1941, (2 copies; Both Inscribed by Author) (Box 40)
  - Myths and Symbols in Indian Art and Civilization by Heinrich Zimmer, 1946, (Inscribed as a Gift) (Box 40)
  - Oversized Clyfford Still by John P. O'Neill, 1979, (Inscribed as a Gift); (See Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized Morphologie Autre by Michel Tapie, 1960, (Inscribed by Author); (See Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized The Waterfall: "Sculptured Water" by Claire Falkenstein, 1965, (from Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized Saint Paul Art Center Third Biennial Exhibition Drawings USA '66, 1966, (from Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized Exhibition of Submitted Works Involving Technical Materials and Processes Organized by Staff and Members of Experiments in Art and Technology, 1968, (from Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized 100 Years of California Sculpture by The Oakland Museum, 1982, (from Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized Manifeste Indirect dans un Temps Autre by Michel Tapie, 1961, (from Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized Art in Los Angeles: Profile 1986, 1986, (from Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized Issue of Vernissage, 1963, 1963, (Volume 4, Number 3, from Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized Issues of Artforum, 1963, 1965, (Volume II, Number 2 and Volume III, Number 7, from Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1951-1957, (from Box 39, F. 17) (Box 45)
  - Oversized Posters, circa 1950-1990, (from Box 39, F. 17) (Box OV 58)